What should I expect during the initial
phase of TRT? What changes might I
notice in the first few months?
I'm going to go on the assumption that
it's being done perfectly correct cuz I
don't know what they're doing and what
they're not doing. So, I can't answer to
your specific situation. But I know for
our patients usually by week three or
four most report an improved sense of
well-being, an improved outlook on life
and future and libido and mood and
desire to be productive and get out of
bed and conquer their day. So it's more
of of a mindset cognition type of an
improvement is the first thing we've
noticed. Um usually
by 3 to 6 month period we'll notice some
body composition changes, increases in
strength, lean body mass, some fat
loss and then usually you'll notice some
cardiovascular improvements that are
measurable whether it be cholesterol,
blood pressure, um arterial function
etc. uh within the first year and some
studies that I have read have said that
even up until the 36 month mark there's
still improvements to bone mineral
density. So there's still an upward
linear curve when it comes to making
your body stronger and improving your
bones for 3 years after initiating
treatment which is beautiful because it
just means that you know you're not done
seeing all the results. Now bone mineral
density is not immediately tangible. We
can't close my eyes and say, "Well, I'm
just imagining my bones are stronger."
But hey, when you take a spill, I mean,
I I've taken some hits accidentally.
I've fallen on my hip. I kind of twisted
my leg once by accident. Um I Things
that normally I should have said, "Damn,
I I I think that would have broke had I
not been on testosterone for a decade."
You know, at my age, I think I would
have broke that leg. Uh I've dropped
things on my foot. You got a lot of
small bones in that foot. I've dropped
things on my foot that are heavy. And I
said, "Oh, I think I just broke my foot
and it's, you know, it's bruised for a
day and I'm I'm fine." And I'm walking
on it and nothing broke. It's, you know,
bones are strong. Bones are strong.
Vitamin D, calcium, good protein, good
sleep, good recovery, and some
testosterone, and your bones are
baseball bats, man. So, yeah, just uh
the longer you stay on, I mean, it's you
should be for life. But know that for
the first 3 years, you're still making
improvements.
[Music]